I decided to do a video this week maybe to help people on trying to understand why they
are still not profitable or at least haven't made a little bit of money in the market.
There's a reason, and very rarely it's a technical reason, sometimes it's because
members probably don't understand the strategy very well but based on what I saw it's always
and almost always mostly psychology.
It seems like there's a pattern that is being built amongst traders, not only you guys everybody
and even me back in the day, and it's patience, the urge of making the money now, the FOMO,
even though some of you guys trade on a $100 account, FOMO and also kind of seeing stuff
in the market that isn't really, how can I say it, that isn't really a thing.
So we'll give an example, I received a question I think two days ago, this was yesterday,
so I received a question of a member who actually saw this, he saw this inducement on the left,
and this video will be all pretty much mixed, it's going to be like a weekly call because
I want to get this out of my chest and try to help most of you guys.
So as you can see there's speed and momentum inducing most likely this Asia midline decisional
POI, even though structural expectations are bullish, most likely intraday here we have
clear liquidity being built, remember it doesn't mean that structural expectation is bullish
that we cannot build sell side liquidity, it's possible.
There's speed and momentum, and there's here a new low made confirming the tradeaway.
Very important, so when you read the chart, and this is going to be me giving you my tips,
you read the chart from left to right, so here we have this making this low, perfect
stop losses, coming back, faking, faking, faking, even better, right?
False reaction, inducement high, right?
So we have one data, oops, one evidence, maybe second evidence because of those multiple
touches of this point, right?
Then third, perfect.
Then here, fourth, inducement, this is a false reaction just so you guys know, look how long
it takes to switch, it's unbelievable, trading view is just horrible, okay?
Now new low here made, so that would be five, right?
And then, oh, reaction from daily low.
So let's do this because if I copy it's going to glitch, six, right?
Perfect.
Then you have some people take the short, you have a reaction of the Asia high PY, and
some members decided to take some shorts over here, right?
And this is because they don't do this pat, right?
Maybe we can call this video the pat to success or the story, right?
And this is exactly what I do in my brain, okay?
So as you can see, you have the steps, and this is members decide to deliberately ignore
this, see?
They decide to also ignore this, this, or they just see this and this, see?
You cannot ignore, and there's even like, let's say a high made here, so that would
be like seven, right?
So you cannot decide to take a trade and ignore clear evidences of the chart, okay?
And this is an example I wanted to give because, and then I asked the member, he took a short
like this.
He said, oh, it's been in momentum to mitigation, and then I did this, and prices are this,
and he felt pissed.
And I asked him how many, and then I asked him how many times in your journal, in your
research, in your data that you have built over the past months with the shelter, how
many times out of 10, let's say, out of 10, it's simple, 10 trade samples has this kind
of setup worked?
From an inducement of Asia high against structural expectation, no real liquidity created, right?
Because right now there's, it's buy side liquidity being built.
So we have liquidity here, and we're about to have relevant one here because it made
a new high.
But we do have it like these zones here, even though it's late in the day, when they enter
here and push, as you can see here, pretty straightforward, boom, boom, boom, right?
So this would also be like, this would be the six, this would be the seven, and this
would be the eight, right?
Because I forgot to mark the liquidity here.
So you're trading against the liquidity, you decide to ignore point eight, seven, six,
and you just tunnel vision point four.
Price needs to be read from left to right.
You cannot ignore something.
It's a no, no, you can't, you just can't, okay?
So let's see what happens after, I think price just continues.
And this is super important.
And as you can see here, when it comes down to other point, let's erase this, erase this,
this, this would be an SMT, right?
Oops, SMT, you could mark now, like maybe because this in turn, even though this internal
break is most likely not so relevant.
I like the fact that a retest is here, right?
Breaking retest.
So this would be the first break of the entry day.
I think that a break and retest here is pretty nice.
And especially it makes a new high here with speed and momentum.
So I think that there's relevance here.
See how I adjust, see how I justify, see, and as you can see here, maybe this took this
little reaction.
Then it came back into the inducement PY from these equal lows.
This is most likely maybe a predicted low.
Who knows?
It made a new high.
It created the FBOS, right?
Engineering most likely the SMT here, right?
We talked about that on another call.
So do you see the reasons why some of you guys are not consistent yet?
And now you can see here, the SMT here, inducement, and there's a potential trade away here.
Unfortunately, this was most likely a pullback because we have the decisional, the inducement
PY.
And the reason why some of you guys don't make money because you don't transform the
strategy into a mechanical approach.
I 100% agree that in some cases, liquidity markups can be a little bit subjective.
Some traders will have two different vision.
This is 100% true when it comes down to markup.
When it comes down to liquidity taken, the outcome cannot be subjective.
And this is why sometimes I do adjustments, and you saw me doing it in my technicals.
I adjust the chart based on newest evidence and based on details that the candle printed
for me.
How can you have bad markups if the chart actually gives you everything, gives you the
details, right?
And in this case, where would be the trade, right?
Pretty much pretty, pretty easy, right?
Can I just remove this?
This is me off.
Where would be the trade?
Very, very easy, right?
As you can see here, there's a mitigation.
You go here.
Price leaves here, makes this relevant break of structure, comes back into the mitigation.
And here we go.
Right?
And this is a trade I took.
I didn't sell to anybody because they would have killed me, but I actually took this trade.
It was the fourth, yeah.
I think we're in the live trading call.
Yeah, yeah, exactly.
Again, read the price in orders.
What are the evidence?
Let's continue the practice.
This is a very good practice, okay?
What is the structural expectation, right?
Point number one is price failed to make a new low, right?
Here, end of day.
Okay?
Now, two, price decides to create kind of equal highs.
Very interesting.
Very, very interesting.
Now, oops.
Now price makes a new low.
Maybe if I do this, it's faster.
Price makes a new low.
So this would be solidification of those equal highs.
Lovely, right?
Do we have relevant liquidity on the sell side?
You can see.
It's not relevant because there's no reaction.
So a lot of people would say, oh, there's stop losses here.
You can do this.
But once it comes here and it doesn't give you any reaction, don't mark up shit, okay?
Now we have faking equal lows.
These equal lows are important.
Why?
Because they are in line with structural expectation.
So this is the new low.
This is the equal lows, right?
We have false reaction.
Ooh, juicy.
We have inducement, right?
And now when there's an inducement of Asia low, what do we do?
We look to the left.
Ooh, potential protected low.
Potential protected low, right?
Asia midline.
Lovely.
So now there's an inducement.
There's clear liquidity target.
There's a mitigation on the left.
Speed and momentum.
Maybe it's time to take a trade, right?
Let's go and see if we have something on the M1.
Lovely.
Lovely POI.
Very, very simple, right?
As you can see, mitigation, right?
I would be taking a trade most likely on the way up after this internal break.
Here we go.
I would wait for this.
Price comes back.
Speed and momentum.
Instant buy.
And you target the equal highs.
Now let's do and let's do our due diligence.
And this is basically what I say by doing our due diligence.
We took a trade based on number six, five, four, three, two, and one.
All these are in line with the same idea.
If there's one of the numbers, let's say here, let's type it.
Oh, God damn it.
What have I done?
God damn it.
I'm sorry.
Let's type them down, right?
Hey, this is annoying.
Failed to make a new low.
End of date.
God damn it.
All right.
Equal, equal highs, right?
From this pullback.
Very lovely.
Number three is new low created.
Confirming equal lows, equal highs.
All right.
Let me just take a sip.
Four.
Equal lows confirmed by multiple touches and respecting structural expectations.
Lovely.
False reaction of equal lows.
Solidifying the liquidity.
Very, very lovely.
Number six.
Speed and momentum inducing equal lows and also Asia low.
Mitigation momentum.
Mitigational from previous date.
Decisional.
Let's put DPY.
Maybe a protected low.
Who knows?
See, let's continue.
Number eight.
Inducement of equal highs.
All right.
Little nine.
Little pullback from inducement of equal highs.
Most likely just relative.
Relative equal highs with not much liquidity.
This has been justified.
By the reaction.
After.
Inducement.
Right.
If this equal highs would be super relevant like this one, we would have made a new low, right?
We just have a little pullback and it continues.
We're just engineering more liquidity.
This is lovely.
It's a mess, but I'm trying to explain to you guys why some of you guys are so lost.
Because you don't do your due diligence.
You don't go step by step.
You cannot justify every single movement.
You just see liquidity.
You just see breakout and you don't ask yourself questions.
And this is a problem.
Price pushes.
Do we have something to the left?
No.
There is a retracement.
Then.
Retracement.
Most likely.
To take liquidity.
Perfect.
Maybe even break and retest.
Who knows?
Lovely, right?
Speed and momentum into it.
Now price comes here.
Revisits the zone.
Let's go check if there's something on the higher time frame.
Not really.
Let's check 30 minutes.
So it's most likely the only thing it's doing.
It's taking this liquidity.
And maybe it's enough.
Maybe we have breakout traders entering here.
And maybe this is breaking them even.
Right?
We don't know.
So number 10.
11.
After inducement.
We get.
A reaction.
Here.
First reaction.
Do we have a new high?
No.
But we have these two structures equaling.
Like this.
For me it's the same thing.
Relevant breakout structure.
Internal breakout structure.
I already said it.
After inducement.
We get a reaction.
Very good.
From the inducement.
Of the breakouts.
And.
Breakouts.
And break and retest.
And the break and retest are a little bit pulled by the hair.
Because of this structure here.
But you get the idea.
It's a breakout or break and retest.
We don't really care.
Then we have a retest of that POI.
Filling the imbalance.
Mitigation.
Oh, wait a minute.
Enticement zone.
Still in play.
Do we have clear liquidity here?
Maybe.
So we can add a little bit of liquidity here.
Possible.
But this is inducement.
So this is a trade away.
And I'm not going to take all the video to explain everything that I do.
This is how I do my daily markups.
If.
You want to be.
Profitable.
You need to bring this mechanical approach.
Of what does the chart.
Tells me.
I would have taken this trade.
Anytime.
The problem is I have too many opportunities.
And I just can't be involved in all these trades.
My brain will just explode.
But these trades are so easy.
Look the way I trade.
I see these structures.
I put an alert here.
Here.
And since I identified.
That maybe we have a little bit of liquidity here.
I put an alert here.
First one that triggers I see if there is a reaction.
That's it.
That's in a nutshell.
How I trade.
You need to have steps by step.
This 11.
Cannot ignore the 10.
Or you cannot ignore the 6.
Look how the 11.
The 10.
The 9.
All in line.
But if we go back into.
Our EU here.
Our GU here.
It's not.
In the same.
Like the 8.
Here.
The 7.
The mitigation of previous daily low.
Most likely an inducement of the S&T.
The new low confirmed.
The speed and momentum.
Of these new lows.
Most likely this is an S&T.
This is a new low.
Maybe an EVBOS.
See how.
The 8.
For taking this trade.
Remember people were taking this trade here.
Like this.
Do you see how.
These numbers are not.
In sync.
The correlation between them.
Is not in sync.
And look at this one.
Everything is in line.
With the trade idea.
This one or this one.
At the second you have something.
It's like if you're putting.
A fake.
Like something that is not.
Part of the dish.
Of the ingredient.
Of the recipe.
You're adding an ingredient.
That doesn't has it's place there.
So the reason I know.
And I know.
I know I'm wrong telling you guys this.
I know some of you guys will say.
It's psychology.
But sometimes.
From what I see.
Psychology can kind of slip.
Into the technicals.
Because you deliberately.
Decide to ignore something.
And do something.
That I have never shown.
And when I ask the members.
The question.
How many times have you seen this.
And indeed.
They can't answer.
And this is not trading.
If you cannot quantify the data.
Of your entry models.
If you're not journaling your trade.
To know exactly what works.
You guys see all my trades.
They are similar.
Why?
Because I know what I like.
I know what I'm doing.
Because I've tested it multiple times.
Why don't you quantify the data.
And just.
Spam this bitch.
Like insanely.
Just spam it.
Do it.
Trading is very rewarding.
But it's rewarding for people.
That actually put in the effort.
To improve.
If you're not doing everything.
In your power.
And you decide to.
When you take a trade.
To ignore this.
You ignore the fact.
That you have right now.
Evidences that tells you.
Not to take the trade.
And you have evidences.
That you basically don't have evidences.
That this trade will work.
Taking a trade from Asia high.
You never back tested this.
This never works.
You don't have the data quantified.
Then why are you taking the trade?
I want to be able to take a trade.
And be able to cut my hand in half.
Because I'm 100% confident.
That I did everything in my power.
To do my due diligence.
To actually understand.
Why I'm taking this trade.
Trust me.
Oh my god.
It takes time.
But it's so rewarding.
Back in the day.
I failed so much FTMOs.
But if you go check my overall.
Withdrawal in FTMO.
So it doesn't matter how much money you lose.
You will make it back.
But you need to continue.
And you need to take this seriously.
Because we know that some of you guys don't take this seriously.
And we see it based on the markups.
You do mechanical markups.
You don't ask yourself questions.
Like the way I do it here.
I want to ask myself questions.
On the chart.
To build this experience.
And to be able.
To record it in my brain.
And actually translate it into life.
It sounds stupid.
But the more you practice.
To do something.
Even though it's not.
Continuously trading.
Actually executing trades.
But you will.
Actually make it.
It's like if you're learning a piano song.
And you constantly practice on your desk.
Without the piano.
Just with the hand movements.
Imagine the piano in front of you.
Your hands.
Your muscle memory.
Will build over time.
And this will be translated into life.
Piano playing.
So.
I hope this helps.
I still don't know how I'm going to call this video.
Maybe like.
Rating the chart.
Or.
Maybe like.
From left to right.
Because we're actually.
This is what I'm saying.
You cannot see this.
You need to identify everything.
And every step one behind the other.
This is a complete mess.
Needs to be.
In line with your idea.
So I think it's.
A very important video.
Do not underestimate this video.
And if you're not.
Where you want to be right now.
It's most likely.
It's also a lot.
About psychology.
But psychology can also impact.
Your actual technical knowledge.
So make sure you think about that.
And if there's anything.
You guys let me know.
And I'll catch you guys all in discord.
Peace.